Sunil Suckoo

(734) 255-5138 sunilsuckoo.github.io ssuckoo16@amherst.edu

Profile

- Experienced social researcher, with a focus on American millennials.
- Proven track record of implementing effective institutional change.
- Interests: random acts of kindness, needle-felting, indie films, event planning.

Skills/Research Methods

Ethnography Field Studies

Diary Studies Interviewing

Survey Design Card Sorting

Focus Groups Presentation

Awards/Honors

Donald S. Pitkin Prize......2016 \$400 to best Anthropology-Sociology thesis out of 12 senior theses.

Watson Fellowship Finalist....2016 6% admission rate, 4 students nominated on practicality and overall strength of research proposal, personal statement, and interview.

Valedictorian......2012 Rank 1 out of 200+ students.

Wilfred D. Webb Award.......2012 The valedictorian with the strongest commitment to community service.

Mathematics Award......2012 \$25 to most promising AP Calculus student out of 20 students.

English/Writing Award...........2012 \$25 to AP English student with the best writing skills out of 25 students.

Education

Amherst College (3.74 GPA) Graduated May 2016

B.A. in Anthropology, Magna Cum Laude Latin Honors

Danish Institute for Study Abroad

August 2014—May 2015

Copenhagen, Denmark

Work Experience

Gregory S. Call Research Fellow June 2015—August 2015

- Conducted preliminary thesis research (literature review, ethnography, field studies, survey design).
- Awarded \$4,280 summer living stipend and full funding (\$1,500+) for several concise (1-3 pages) and in-depth (10-15 pages) thesis research proposals and itemized budgets.

Resident Counselor (RC)

August 2013-May 2016

Amherst College Office of Student Affairs

- Designed and issued 10+ surveys with 100% response rate.
- Planned 20+ events with nearly perfect attendance (20-25 students) using survey data and ethnographic insights.
- Co-founded the RC Council, which successfully advocated for a 30% increase in salary and 150% increase in yearly budget.

Mellon Initiative Research Fellow

June-August 2014

University of Chicago

- Conducted qualitative research (ethnography, field studies, interviews, card sorting) and data analysis on Amherst College diversity initiatives.
- Presented at the Leadership Alliance National Symposium (350+ undergraduates, 50 grad students, 25 doctoral scholars) and Chicago Research Symposium (20+ scholars).

Research Projects

Millennial Cyborgs (Senior Thesis)

 Wrote 110-page user-centered research on American millennials' based on 5+ years of ethnography, field studies, diary studies, and interviews, and 140+ survey responses.

 Received praise from 50+ students, 20+ doctoral scholars, and 10+ business professionals at the Five College Anthropology Conference for its clarity and potential for improving the technology-rich lives of millennials.

Diversity at Amherst College

June—August 2014

June 2015—May 2016

 Successfully recommended 10 new paid staff positions for the diversity centers to Amherst College President based on student-driven research conducted as a Research Fellow.

A Simulation of Economic Inequality

January—May 2013

 Led a team of five to recruit students for age-based focus groups (4-6 people) to participate in experimental simulations and semi-structured qualitative interviews.